I used to be a much more judgmental
person than I currently am a big reason
I used to be in him no longer judgmental
is I have this weird when I call like
reverse karma or when I'm judgmental
about something it shows up in my life
and with both of my parents the thing I
was most judgmental about them with are
exactly what I inherited from them even
with friends and roommates the things
that I was like that cannot be a thing
are things that showed up in my own life
as a parent and I think this is where it
happens in many people's lives before
you're a parent you have this idea of
exactly how you're gonna raise your kid
right my kids never gonna misbehave in
public for me it was my kid when my
birth was gonna go I was gonna have a
natural birth at home I was gonna
breastfeed and my kid was never gonna
have sugar or have screentime I ended up
with a c-section the hospital I had to
formula feed for a while and because you
know life has its own its own agenda
I my kid absolutely has screen time all
of the time and eats sugar daily and now
like I can see why like right because
this is easier because it it our culture
is so intertwined with these things my
parents two of the main the things I was
judgmental on was when I was a teenager
I mama had I think for the first time
although maybe interplay with the rest
of her life as well
chronic fatigue and fibromyalgia and
watch her I'm um kind of not having it
during our childhood and then having it
I was like right no you're depressed get
off the couch get off the couch and now
that my daughter is born and I had high
stress trigger mine I absolutely I'm
like oh now I get it
yes chronic fatigue and fire mild your
whole body's in pain your whole body is
exhausted and there's no explanation for
it there are little things you can do to
improve it nothing nothing greatly my
dad when he was in his late 30s came out
as bi
well he I had known him as you know my
mom and dad were together until I was 15
and then they split up but my dad
doesn't date so like my judgmental side
was like oh good so now you're gonna not
date men the same way you don't date
women like this is sure you can be
bisexual and not at like and be asexual
more or less and that is Who I am like I
didn't realize I was clear until my late
30s I haven't kissed a woman because of
my health conditions and my demisexual
which is on the a sexual spectrum and so
I'm like but it's from inside it's not
something that someone else labels you
as or society puts on you I had a
roommate who was both poly and asexual I
was like that can't be a big poster
opposite sides of a spectrum and now I
kind of am both of those things I'm like
oh I don't know if I want to have just
one partner if I did was gonna have
partners I don't I don't know and yet I
don't know if I have the capacity to
have more than even one let alone more
than one and so now it's funny when I
hear other people who aren't parents who
are judgmental about parent so much
don't say it it's gonna be if you're
gonna be a parent you're gonna get the
thing don't don't say it but I don't
know if everyone has this happen in
their lives constantly it happens for me
and now that enough of them have
happened I'm grateful for it because now
in the moment when I'm judgmental about
someone like a note stop talking
judgmental one you don't know you not in
their shoes and I can also see it as
what it was which is like their thing
would trigger this subconscious
knowledge of what I am but not accepting
in myself
and so I am both very grateful for my
judgmental self and it has greatly
evaporated there's very few things I'm
judgmental for people on the one
probably being like I don't know like
like
what is currently propped up in society
so capitalistic rich you think you're
entitled to everything just because you
have money I am still judgmental about
that and dear goodness if I'm what I'm
looking forward to having to experience
that on the other side oh look now I'm
rich let's see let's see if I'm still
that person I don't think I will be
because that judgment comes from a
different place
that's unfairness on a grand scale and I
don't think that you've earned it
because nobody earns it none of us are
more entitled to love and connection and
resources and health and community than
anybody else you're entitled to
someone's community like you can't force
people to be friends with you but you're
not entitled to you know having better
health care getting first in line of
organs getting first in line at the
coffee shop that know people I know who
who are a little narcissistic and rich
it's like the more narcissistic you are
the easier it is to get rich and then
the more you feel that you're entitled
to be enriched because you've got rich
and you tried hard to do it anyway so
they look at that there comes out my
judgment it's not like I'm at zero
I haven't send out you know all of my
judgment but this character trait has
been a blessing thank you